otc.edu 2011-05-25

# Website Privacy Policies

### Website Privacy Policies

**OTC Web Site Privacy Policy**  
Information and services offered on otc.edu are provided by Ozarks Technical Community College (OTC), Springfield, Missouri. The purpose of the site is to provide public information about the college, and to offer online services to students, college faculty and staff. Online services include, but are not limited to college admission, class registration, tuition payment, financial aid, and class schedules. Ozarks Technical Community College recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy rights of our users. Any private information, as defined by FERPA(Link to Policy) and all other applicable laws,  policies, and guidelines shared between users and Ozarks Technical Community College, is securely managed and safeguarded. 

**Changes to privacy policy**  
Ozarks Technical Community College may need to change our privacy statement because of changes in the law, in technology, in Ozarks Technical Community College's business, or in our attempts to serve your needs better. We will use every effort to communicate in a timely manner any changes to our privacy statement in the manner described in the Ozarks Technical Community College Site Terms and Conditions.

 **What information does Ozarks Technical Community College gather?**  
When you visit otc.edu, OTC�s web server automatically recognizes only the Internet domain and IP address from which you accessed the web site. This information does not result in the identification of your personal e-mail address or other personal information.  In addition, OTC gathers information regarding the volume and timing of access to our web site by collecting information on the date, time and web site pages accessed by visitors. We do this so we can improve the content of otc.edu and this information is not shared with other organizations. Again, only aggregate information is collected and individual visitors� personal information is not identified.

If you choose to share personal information with us � by sending us a message, live chat, logging into my.otc.edu, or filling out an electronic form with personal information � we will use the information only for the purposes you authorized or in support of College sponsored programs. Some of the information may be saved for a designated period of time to comply with Missouri�s archiving policies, but we will not disclose the information to other third parties or government agencies, unless required to do so by state or federal law or in support of college sponsored programs. If we are required to disclose information about you by law, we will make every effort to notify you of the disclosure in advance. 

Online services that are accessible through my.otc.edu provide password-protected access to individuals� personal records including, but not limited to, personal contact information, class records information and tuition-payment history. This information is accessible only by the individual and approved college administrative staff. 

**How the information is used**  
Information gathered through otc.edu is used to improve the web site experience for our visitors, prospective students, existing students, and employees. Information captured in my.otc.edu enables users to access their personal records and utilize online services offered by Ozarks Technical Community College. 

**Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act**  
The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) of 1974, as amended, provides students access to information about themselves, permits students to challenge such information about themselves, and limits the release of such information about students without the student�s explicit written consent.

OTC is committed to this Act in its entirety. Procedural guidelines are available by clicking here, in appropriate College publications, and copies of procedures may be obtained from the Records Office.

 **Access to student records**  
A student�s record, with certain exceptions including directory information (see below), will not be released without prior written consent of the student. A student has the right to review and question the content of her/his educational record within a reasonable time (45 days) after making a written request for such a review. If there are any questions as to the accuracy or appropriateness of the record that cannot be resolved informally, an opportunity for a hearing on the matter will be provided.

 **Disclosure of education records**  
OTC does not disclose student education records to anyone unless the student has  
provided to the College a written and dated consent for disclosure of the record, or the  
disclosure meets one of the allowable exceptions under the law.

There are certain exceptions that permit the College to disclose student education  
records without student consent. These exceptions include:  

  * To school officials with legitimate educational interests 
  * To schools in which a student seeks or intends to enroll 
  * To Federal, State, and local authorities conducting an audit, evaluation, or enforcement of educational programs 
  * In connection with financial aid 
  * To entities conducting educational research 
  *  To accrediting organizations 
  * To parents of a dependent student 
  * To comply with judicial order or subpoena provided that the institution make a reasonable attempt to notify the student in advance of compliance 
  * In a health or safety emergency 
  * Directory information 
  * Results of a disciplinary hearing to an alleged victim of a crime of violence 
  * Final results of a disciplinary hearing concerning a student who is an alleged perpetrator of a crime of violence and who is found to have committed a violation of the institution�s rules or policies. 
  * Disclosure to the parent of a student under 21 if the institution determines that the student has committed a violation of its drug or alcohol rules or policies 
  * The Department of Homeland Security for purposes related to the Student Exchange and Visitor Information System (SEVIS) 
  * Military recruiters who request student-recruiting information (including name, address, telephone listing, age level of education and major)
  * The Department of Veterans Affairs 
  * The Internal Revenue Service in compliance with the Taxpayer Relief Act  

**Directory information  
** OTC designates certain personally identifiable information that is contained within the student�s education record as �directory information� so that the College may, at its discretion, disclose this information without a student�s prior written consent. This information is student name, home address and telephone number, e-mail address, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized activities, current enrollment status (including dates of attendance, full or part time, withdrawal status). A student may restrict the publication and release of this directory information by filing a written request with the Records Office.  
In addition, the following information is always considered releasable: previous dates of attendance, degrees and awards received (to include honors), previous educational agencies or institutions attended. The complete policy regarding the collection, retention and dissemination of information about a student is available in the Records Office.

 **Live Chat  
** OTC uses live chat to engage prospective students, existing students, employees, and visitors to the website. Live Chat operators can only provide general information and answers to �How To�, �Where do I�, �When is the� questions. No personal, identifiable information can be released using this method. This includes but is not limited to admissions status, financial aid status, grades, and payments or cashier information. Transcripts of all chat sessions are kept on file for a period of 24 hours then destroyed. 

**Cookies**  
Our website may places "cookies" on your computer, unless your browser is set to reject cookies. The cookies enable our website to recognize you when you return to the website at a later date or time and enable us to personalize the website with preferences or information you have provided during prior sessions.

 **Links to other websites**  
Our website may contain links to other public or private entities' websites, whose privacy practices we do not control.

 **Choice to provide information**  
There is no requirement for you to provide any information at our website. However, the online services will not be available to you without proper login. Failure of your browser to provide nonessential technical information will not prevent your use of our website, but may prevent you from accessing online services. 

**Visitor comments or review**  
If you have questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this website or if you choose to review or correct any information, please contact us at [web@otc.edu](mailto:web@otc.edu), or call 417-447-7556.
